[AWAKEN]
[Episode 10]
The nerve of you to show up.
Where did you take her?
Is she already dead?
Did you kill her?
Say something!
Raise your gun.
Raise it!
Are you going to shoot me dead?
You don't even know how to shoot.
You can't blow my head off with one shot.
You can't protect yourself,
yet you want to save others!
Listen up.
What's the use of a camera?
Can it turn into a bullet
that pierces through my skull?
Remember:
she is a Communist.
Stop thinking about her.
Otherwise,
I'll have to suspect
you're in league with her!
Yes!
I am!
I'm in league with her!
I'm also a Communist!
There's no Communist
as stupid as you in this world.
To me,
whether she is a Communist or not,
I don't care at all.
In these times,
aren't people's stances always changing?
When I met you,
you were protecting this country.
Now,
who is your gun protecting...
and who is it aimed at?
Right now,
before saving the country,
I have to save myself.
Even the heavens
wouldn't believe that.
Knowing Auntie for so long,
how have I never taken a picture of her?
Her picture wasn't taken,
so why did she get sucked away too?
Spring thunder roars, all things grow.
Today is The Awakening of Insects,
the 20th of the first lunar month.
What a splendid day.
Get out.
Women shouldn't be so stubborn.
What you said,
even the God of Thunder wouldn't agree.
Have a safe trip.
Get out!
Then I'll take my leave.
Remember:
just stick with me
and you'll rise to the top
and live the high life with fine dining.
Fine dining?
Is it as good as Yangzhou fried rice?
Don't worry.
There's plenty of Yangzhou fried rice too.
Commendation Order,
Order No. 195.
Du Huangqiao of
the Special Operations Division
of the National Military Council
fought a fierce battle against the NBIS
during the operation to eliminate
the leaders of the 12th Branch.
Calm and decisive,
wise and brave,
he thwarted the evil plots of the NBIS
and boosted the prestige of our army.
A special commendation is hereby issued
as encouragement.
Keep up the good work.
Cleaner,
welcome back.
Only two bodies were found at the scene.
Look around again! Now!
Yes!
Maybe after obtaining the address,
that female Communist noticed something
and a fight broke out.
The scene was burned beyond recognition.
Only two charred bodies were found.
I don't believe
two men couldn't even handle
an injured woman.
The men were sent by No. 76 in Hangzhou.
They were personally trained
by Lu Xiaoguang, a Communist
who was recently turned.
He dreams of
being transferred to Shanghai.
So he wouldn't have
sent losers over.
Maybe he messed up and fled,
afraid of being
held accountable.
But I've been keeping an eye on him.
Not a word will leak out.
Although the Communist forces are small,
their ability cannot be underestimated.
The matter of the female Communist
is over.
It doesn't matter if she's dead or not.
But there's one thing
that's been weighing on my mind.
What is it?
During the rescue operation
at Renji Hospital,
two people from Operations also died.
That was definitely not done by my people.
So,
the Communists were also
preparing a rescue operation.
They were just a step behind you.
You mean...
we have a mole in No. 76?
Mr. Zhao.
Who?
Zhao Qian.
He caught the Communist himself.
I sent him there.
Look at you.
You've been Cleaner for so long that
you're unable to trust anyone.
Indeed.
It'd be horrifying if
he were a Communist.
To doubt our own,
you need solid evidence.
He and Su Men aren't the same kind.
Su Men's your biggest worry.
Just one word from you,
and I can make her disappear anytime.
It's good to have you back.
In the current No. 76,
there are fewer and fewer people to trust,
and more and more
eyes watching me.
Well, there used to be Yu,
but it's a shame
he turned out to be a disappointment.
Has his ledger
been dealt with?
I had Yu Yingxiang
take the ledger to the bathhouse.
Kill him,
and bring the ledger back.
Where's the ledger?
In the briefcase.
Are you... seeing me off?
Yes.
I'll personally send you on your way.
There were too many
prying eyes at Fairy Bath.
I was worried I'd lose the ledger,
so I destroyed it.
Saving you back then was
the right choice.
You saved my life.
If you want it,
you can take it anytime.
You're awake.
My wife and daughter are dead.
You should've let me die with them.
It's the party-state you serve
that abandoned you
and your family.
Look.
The sun is so bright today.
All that happened yesterday
died with yesterday.
All that happens today
lives with today.
The Du Huangqiao
who lived for the party-state
died yesterday.
The new Du Huangqiao
should live
for himself from now on.
From today on,
I, Du Huangqiao,
will not only live for myself,
but also for you.
I believe in your capabilities.
And I believe in your loyalty even more.
Now that you're back,
what position do you want?
I'll follow your arrangements, Director.
Effective today,
you'll take the post
of Captain
of the Direct Action Brigade of No. 76.
Thank you, Director.
Director,
I'd like to bring someone else in.
Who?
Chen Kailai.
The photographer.
What use could
a photographer be?
He saved my life,
and I saved his.
We've been through
life and death together.
He's very smart.
If I personally train him,
he could become a pillar of No. 76.
You can decide who you want to recruit.
But before using anyone,
you must vet their background thoroughly.
Chen Kailai is
very close to Su Men.
That's exactly one of the reasons
I want him.
Also,
Cang Guanglian will be under your command.
I know there's
bad blood between you two,
but you must understand
that you're both my right-hand men.
Rest assured, Director.
Big or small,
I know my priorities.
Inspector Su.
Captain Du, to think you'd even
try to pull a fast one on me.
Inspector Su,
it's my fault.
What I did behind the director's back
accidentally got you hurt.
Punish me as you see fit.
What a loyal dog.
At the entrance of Fairy Bath,
there was a local dog named Yeller.
We used to be quite close.
Unfortunately, yesterday...
I accidentally got it hurt.
Then I hope you don't end up like it.
Thank you for your forgiveness,
Inspector Su.
This lousy stormy weather—
it's going to rain again.
The world is
full of unpredictable twists and turns.
When some succeed,
others fail.
If you're the one succeeding,
then I must be the one failing.
That's not what I meant.
In the decades
since the fall of the Qing Dynasty,
the rulers of this land have changed
again and again.
Today it's you.
Tomorrow it's me.
Who knows
who will have the last laugh?
Who do you think it will be, Inspector Su?
Whoever lives the longest.
Do what I said immediately.
Rest assured, Director Li.
Understood?
Director Li.
Director Li, nice to meet you.
Congratulations.
Congrats.
Welcome back, Captain Du.
Captain of the Direct Action Brigade.
When it comes to being well-informed,
it has to be you, Sachiko.
You wiped out the 12th Branch of NBIS
in one fell swoop.
You're now the favorite of No. 76.
You also deserve some credit for this.
I'm glad you remember.
Of course I do.
If it weren't for your help,
how could I have gathered
the 12th Branch of NBIS
all together?
Sell this intel to the Hurricane Team.
What is this place?
The address of the Project Slumber lab.
They definitely want it.
From now on, I'll be
counting on you at No. 76.
Rest assured.
As long as I'm here,
I'll take good care of you.
Thank you.
A glass of wine.
That blind man invited you too?
I'm not here for him.
He's riding high right now.
You now have a backer at No. 76.
Who cares?
Mr. Zhao, you're really
smooth and tactful.
You can make friends with anyone.
The three of us have bathed together.
It's a special bond.
How about a nickname for us?
The Three Heroes of the Bathhouse.
That's a good nickname!
What's so good about it?
Fairy Bath's done anyway.
Don't worry.
I'll make sure
the "Fairy Bath" sign stands tall again.
The sign is still there.
It's just a pity about the boss.
She's already dead.
What's the use of dwelling on it?
Who would've thought
that such a wonderful person
was actually from the NBIS?
And who would've thought
that a blind man is actually...
A traitor.
Right?
I know.
You all think I was too heartless.
But in this world,
life forces everyone's hand at some point.
She chose the wrong side,
so death is her best ending.
I understand.
Letting her suffer less is
also your way of looking out for her.
Ridiculous.
Killing someone is looking out for them?
You lot are insane.
I was like him when I was younger.
Mr. Zhao, you've been sandbagging.
You caught that female Communist.
It was pure luck.
Director Li specifically asked me
to make up the numbers that day.
I realized that
as long as it's about the Communists,
you're particularly attentive.
Wait.
What's wrong?
You reminded me.
Why am I not included
in this batch of commendations?
Could the credit have
all gone to Cang Guanglian?
Li Moqun
and Du the Blind...
They teamed up to play me.
One Yu Yingxiang wasn't enough.
They even sent a female Communist.
In all this,
I'm the only fool,
being played like a fiddle.
Especially that Du the Blind,
he's just a dog.
Come on.
Let's drink up today.
May I have this dance?
With your dancing skills? No thanks.
What did you capture?
My miserable state?
I don't think you look miserable.
Sometimes people look better
when they don't smile.
That's not a bad answer.
Then can I ask you something?
I know what you're going to ask.
Is she really dead?
It's already in the newspapers.
Newspaper headlines change every day.
But I believe
your words.
She's dead.
What did she say?
The dead cannot come back to life.
But we must
keep the grudge in our hearts.
It's all my fault.
It's my fault that there isn't a photo
of Auntie.
It's also my fault
that my cousin died.
I shouldn't have trusted that blind man.
Let's not cry.
The living must live well.
We must live well for them.
Boss, Cang Guanglian's here.
He's in your office.
I told his fortune before.
If he wants to live to 89,
he must beware of people
with "shu (tree)" in their names.
I've lived my whole life
with eyes that don't work.
Battalion Commander,
please...
please punish me.
I wronged you in the past.
That day, I rushed back
to the camp for reinforcements.
But there was no one left in the camp.
Everyone was afraid of death
and ran away.
Get up!
Take it!
Later,
I took my gun to go save you.
But as soon as I went out,
I ran into the Japanese.
Battalion Commander.
I misunderstood you.
Battalion Commander,
from now on, whatever your orders are,
I will never say no!
What if I order you
to swallow these right now?
Swallow them!
Buddy,
if you make too big a deal out of this,
you're insulting me.
I was just joking with you.
In this world,
many things
are just meant to be.
Take us for example.
We are
brothers who braved death together
on the battlefield!
What you need to do now
is to forget everything
about Nanjing and the bathhouse!
It was all just a joke.
Because
life forces everyone's hand at some point.
Am I right?
Battalion Commander...
Pal.
I need you to do something for me.
Commander, just give the order.
Keep an eye on him.
From now on,
no one is to mention Auntie again.
Isn't she like a sister to you?
Only those who
[Xiaoxian]
forget the dead
can go on living.
You too.
Du the Blind,
don't shed crocodile tears here.
It's disgusting.
Wait.
Take this.
I have enough clothes.
Enough for the photo studio,
but not for No. 76.
Why would I go to No. 76?
I told you
our hard times are over.
Join me at No. 76 and live the high life.
That's you.
That shark tank
is not a place for me.
It's precisely
because it's a shark tank
that
I need you there with me.
Why?
Because I can't trust anyone there.
I only trust you.
But I don't trust you anymore.
You don't understand
people or politics.
You'll suffer in the outside world.
Like I said,
following the right person is important.
And like I said,
I'm just a photographer.
I don't follow anyone.
Think it over again.
Unless you tie me up and take me.
I'm a blind man
who can tell fortunes.
I foresee that one day,
you'll come begging me.
Impossible.
Boss, you're back.
Mr. Zhao sent someone to deliver this,
saying it's to pay respects to Xiaoxian.
People from No. 76 have no conscience.
They're all accomplices.
Get rid of it right away.
The departed
deserve remembrance.
Put them in a vase.
By the way,
I left the newspaper you ordered
on the stand.
Newspaper?
The Shen Bao.
The newsboy said you ordered it.
Captain,
Mr. Zhao either goes to the dance hall
or eats out.
Except for different female companions,
I haven't seen anything unusual.
That Du guy is deliberately
making things difficult for me.
He just gives me useless crap to do.
Thank you, Mr. Zhao.
Surnamed Su,
cousin,
the 25th,
went missing in the bathhouse...
No. 13, Yaoshuinong Shantytown,
South Bank of Suzhou Creek.
Rickshaw!
To Yaoshuinong Shantytown,
South Bank of Suzhou Creek.
Okay, sir.
Sit tight.
Well...
Mr. Zhao, what a coincidence.
You came alone?
Didn't bring a date?
I'm not like you,
having a date with a beauty.
How can you come here without a date?
Do you know Lillian?
Now, she's the most sought-after
in all of Shanghai.
I'll help you jump the queue.
He's Captain Cang.
Mr. Zhao and I are old friends.
Mr. Zhao's friends are my friends.
Miss Lillian,
I've heard so much about you.
Captain Cang,
let's dance.
Mr. Zhao, join us.
You go have fun.
I'll order some drinks.
I'll be right back.
I'll be waiting.
Hello?
♪ Rose, oh rose, most lovely ♪
♪ Rose, oh rose, most ravishing ♪
♪ Blooming upon branches
through long summer days ♪
♪ Rose, oh rose, I love you ♪
♪ Rose, oh rose, your sentiment profound ♪
How dare you, Cang Guanglian!
♪ Rose, oh rose, your affection deep ♪
Didn't you say you had a mission?
So you came here for this vixen!
No, no.
Stop right there!
♪ Blooming through the summer
amid the thorns ♪
I really have a mission.
You lied to me again! Move!
Who the hell are you? Where are you from?
♪ Rose, oh rose, I love you ♪
What's your name?
Let me look at you!
♪ The vow of the heart,
the devotion of the soul ♪
Let them handle their family affairs.
We'll just dance.
Why were you dancing with him?
Alright, alright!
♪ A sacred radiance
illuminates the earth ♪
Let's go home. We'll talk at home.
What home?
Let's go home. Come on!
♪ The vow of the heart,
the devotion of the soul ♪
Let go of me!
Let go!
♪ A sacred radiance
illuminates the earth ♪
♪ Rose, oh rose, slender are your stems ♪
Cang told me a couple of days ago
that he wanted to ask you out.
Maybe he followed us
♪ Rose, oh rose, sharp are your thorns ♪
here on purpose today.
No wonder you paired him up
♪ Wind and rain may come to ravage today ♪
with that Lillian.
Don't worry, Mr. Zhao.
♪ Bruising the tender twigs
and dainty petals ♪
To me,
you'll always be number one.
♪ Rose, oh rose, steadfast is your heart ♪
I don't believe that.
Your acting's so good
that you even fooled
that female Communist.
♪ Rose, oh rose,
piercing are your prickles ♪
It's a pity you didn't see
my performance that day
with your own eyes.
♪ Though future storms
may come to batter the blossoms ♪
♪ They cannot destroy the branches
that intertwine as one ♪
I was excellent.
How did you do it?
I've never seen anyone
who could imitate her so well.
♪ Rose, oh rose, most lovely ♪
Who said I haven't seen her?
General Kagesa arranged for me to see her
♪ Rose, oh rose, most ravishing ♪
at the Plum Blossom Agency.
Otherwise,
I wouldn't have been able to
♪ Blooming upon branches
through long summer days ♪
replicate the elegant temperament
of that Shanghai woman.
There aren't many elegant women
left in Shanghai.
♪ Rose, oh rose, I love you ♪
It's a pity for her to die.
♪ Rose, oh rose, your sentiment profound ♪
I doubt the Japanese would kill her.
♪ Rose, oh rose, your affection deep ♪
She comes from a powerful family.
Her father does business in Japan.
♪ Blooming through the summer
amid the thorns ♪
I heard his business is quite large.
♪ Rose, oh rose, I love you ♪
The Japanese are still
somewhat wary of him.
Is she still at the Plum Blossom Agency?
♪ The vow of the heart,
the devotion of the soul ♪
You seem to be very interested in her.
♪ A sacred radiance
illuminates the earth ♪
I figured she must be very beautiful,
♪ The vow of the heart,
the devotion of the soul ♪
or they wouldn't have
asked you to play her.
♪ A sacred radiance
illuminates the earth ♪
You sure know how to
catch people off guard
with those compliments of yours.
♪ Rose, oh rose, slender are your stems ♪
Sir, stop here.
Here you go.
Thank you, sir.